You
How many times have I done this
This circle always sends me somewhere different
But in the end
I always wind up back here
Something tells me
I won't get many more chances
There's still so much I wanted to do
I wanted to be a teacher
I wanted a taste of normal happiness
Like my mom and dad have
I want to fall in love
I want to get married
But instead
I'm going to die in here
Those dreams will never come true
I don't want to die
Thank goodness
What?
My apologies
It's because of the smell
I'm sorry
Do I stink?
No I do
I didn't mean you
I've been stuck down here
For an entire month
No problem
I don't mind one bit
Well I mind a lot
No
What I mean to say is
Thank you for rescuing me
I could have died here
Of course
What else was I going to do?
Well anyway
I am extremely pleased
To make your acquaintance
Good sir
I'm Roxy
Would you mind telling me
What your name is?
Pleased to make your acquaintance?
Huh?
Oh
Have we met before?
Sorry
I can't recall
You don't
Remember me?
I can't believe
All you
I can't actually
Have I met
You
Nice
Ah
I'm
To be continued...
...to bail you out for a change.
The smell doesn't bother you?
It made Rudy throw up, so it must be even worse than I thought.
It wasn't that. I was so happy that I finally got to see you again.
And when you didn't remember me, my stomach just knotted up.
It's not like I'd forgotten who you are.
It's more like I didn't connect the cute little Rudy that I remember to the way you look these days.
Losing my lunch can't have made a good impression, but the shock really hit me hard.
I wonder if this is how Sylphie felt when I tried to reintroduce myself.
I should apologize again when I get home.
Everyone was happy about Roxy's return.
Good news is welcome, even if you're only filling a hole you dug yourself.
We gave her a few days of nothing but bed rest and good food, so she could focus on recovering her strength.
She'll be back at it in no time.
Good morning, Master Roxy! How are you feeling?
Fine now. I apologize for putting you through so much trouble.
You needn't fret about that one bit.
But if you thank someone, thank Rudy.
He started babbling,
Dad, Dad, I can sense a goddess nearby, and he went off smashing through the wall.
We never would have found you otherwise.
Is that so?
I suppose, um, thanks so much, Rudeus.
Oh, you're incredibly welcome.
I'm so happy I could help.
And hey, just call me Rudy like you used to.
But that would be weird, wouldn't it?
Sounds overly familiar to me.
Beats overly formal.
Look, if I'm gonna make my master use my full name,
then I might as well make my father call me that, too.
I'll tell you right now I'm not doing it.
We're still close.
Be as free with me as you ever were.
No matter how many years pass, you are my master,
and I will always be your student.
All right, then.
You have a point, Rudy.
Thanks, Master.
All that aside, you've gotten really tall.
Well, I am human.
I see you haven't changed a bit.
Yep, I'm still tiny.
I don't think you're as small as you think you are.
Really?
Huh.
I said we'd wait and see about Roxy's health,
but I'm thinking we ought to dive back in there in about three days.
That's a little soon, isn't it?
It's best for Roxy to get back in a labyrinth before too long.
Hmm.
Well, yeah, I guess you got a point.
I hadn't thought of that.
How's that make sense?
Don't you think we should give her all the rest she needs?
Yeah, I figure you might not know about this, boss.
But when you have a close call in a labyrinth,
you gotta go back real quick.
Or else you'll be cursed and you'll never be able to enter again.
A curse, huh?
I wonder if that's how this world sees trauma.
For the moment, let's focus on mapping out the rest of the third level.
Depending on how we're feeling once we're there,
I want to at least go deep enough to find the circle to the fourth level.
Roxy, you should give this a read.
Rudy brought us a book on the teleporter labyrinth.
Wow, a whole book, huh?
Thank you, Paul.
I'll start reading it first thing in the morning.
All right.
You have three days, so use them well.
Break.
Um, Rudy?
Yes, Master? How can I help you?
Your pacing in front of me like that is a little distracting.
I'm sorry about that.
If you're free, there are a few things in this book I'm not quite clear on.
Can you-
Yes, please ask me anything!
Well, can you explain this part?
Yeah, of course.
So, the monsters have fixed areas of activity.
Man, Roxy is kind of small, isn't she?
She used to look like a giant to me.
I bet she'd fit on my lap these days.
I'm not gonna say anything like that, though.
Cool, huh?
Is there something wrong, Master?
No, I was just thinking...
She does seem self-conscious about her height.
And now I'm so much taller.
Maybe it bugs her more than I thought.
Icicle bail!
Good work, everyone.
i'm about to run out of mana i'd like to take a short break sure i tell you i really wish that
circle to the fourth level would show itself already think we can afford to pick up the
pace a little bit sure just as long as you don't go blasting through any more walls boss
you're gonna cause a cave-in i know rudy what's up would you mind if i leaned against your back for a
minute no help yourself this is kind of odd huh i never thought we'd get to explore a labyrinth
together me neither
fruity once we rescue your mother and can both spare some time what do you want to tackle another
one with me what like just the two of us yes normally these things can make for a pretty
fun adventure so if you wanted to form a party we could try out an easier one together that sounds
great let's give it a shot once we get back is that a promise yep promise
i just got sleepy can i doza please sweet dreams i agreed in the heat of the moment but i'll have
a kid to race by then will i really have time for dungeon crawling eh we can wait till i do
what's the plan geese we haven't run into supplies just yet all right we'll scope out the fourth
stratum before we head back let's get a move on you know paul's pretty suave when he's on the job
rudy enemies stone cannon coming in hot rudy hold on i've heard that the armored warriors primarily
use the water god style if you're not careful they'll just counter your magic right back at us
what should i do then root them in place and stick to support understood hey dad i'm about to cast
quagmire watch your footing yeah paul you take the right one and i'll take the left roger that
you always take the left don't you i can fight a lot better without a wall blocking my sword hand
oh please you just pick your
hey alina lease needs some backup right now yes ma'am the magic blade of ice strike clean and true
icicle edge don't kill her
well damn guess these a-ranked bastards put up a fight don't they
dad is it just me or have you gotten a lot stronger over the years
i uh can't say i have no if anything i've gotten weaker now look alive let's move out
when you're exploring a labyrinth frequent trips back to town are the norm
but if we keep moving this slow what are the chances zenith will still be alive
and i need a weapon to help me cut down the steel-plated brutes
no we've got to avoid rushing and making things even worse slow and steady
if you need supplies for a labyrinth rupon's the place to be you know if you make a scroll
shiera will write out the duplicates for you that's a good pointer thank you roxy
we could splash some of that oil on the ground might help take down the armored warriors right
it would be just as effective against your father
oh rudy let's grab a talfro root too okay
a blade like that is perfect for elena lease well how much is it way too much
you're telling me you were in windport at the same time we were
yes it's true but i didn't realize that we'd missed each other until it was too late
i can't tell you how grateful i am that you looked for my family it means a lot
for them i was honored your parents took great care of me
my master and i had a falling out you could say but after that i had no place left to go
not until your parents took me in
and back then i was so afraid of being looked down on i felt the need to brag and exaggerate
are you kidding me you've always been incredible not true if it weren't for you
i wouldn't have learned the limits of my own power how like as soon as i taught you step one
you'd already worked out step 10 or 20 without anybody's help only because you taught me so well
thanks to you i decided to go back to basics and reached king class i suppose i matured
emotionally too my friends noticed and showered me with praise
for me those two years back in buena village they were some of the most important of my life
of course which is why we have to save zenith yeah
looks like this room's got the only circle left in the fourth stratum
thanks to our elaborate prep the fourth stratum was a breeze but still no sign of zenith
just like the book said this talfo room works wonders good no turning back let's keep going then sir yes
the guardian must be close by i'm pretty sure that i can feel it too
same keep your eyes up and don't let your guard down
i don't know which one looks like the guy who wrote the book only made it this far
i can help out oh thanks boss
yep sure looks like the two-way circles we've used a bunch of times already
but according to the book it'll warp us somewhere random
rudy any of this makes sense no i wish that nanahoshi could figure this out though
oh uh nanahoshi your girlfriend nothing like that we're just friends
well make any progress nope not at all if the book is right out of the three remaining circles one is
a trap and only one of the remaining two will take us where we need to go i see classic coin flip
it certainly seems that way oh heavens me you can't coin flip
am i missing something here just as poor luck we always fail coin flips unless we let gilane choose for us
i have an idea but i need more time i'd like to investigate some more
okay that's fine your call
good because something's bugging me being in here i can tell the room is special but i can't say why
you seem a little lost
i am it's just there has to be more to the stratum than this something just isn't adding up what if
there's another route we might have missed there isn't one well i know that the stratum ends here for
sure based on what nothing well i'll need to rush this and you don't have to figure this out on your
own okay right oh and while we're both over here there's something i've been wanting to talk with
you about yeah what's that hmm uh nah now's not the right time when we get back to the end we'll have
a chat oh come on seriously people call those famous last words relax will you i can't now it could
affect the whole party's morale so you want to lecture me or what a lecture yeah something like that
now you see these days i've been keen on using two swords one used to be enough to satisfy me but
now your old man's grown used to having both i'm attached to both and they play different roles
eh you'll get it one day
wait i've seen this room before and recently too
except something's missing
that's right it looks like the ruins we used to get here
that's right here hey geese what's up would you mind checking around this area for a hidden
staircase please huh you know what it's possible
right here it sounds hollow i think i might have found it will we be okay if i break the floor
yeah no traps okay boss go for it right here
all right hey guys it looks like this ain't the last room of the stratum after all
you've got it hell yeah that's my boy for you come to think of it it looks like the ruins we used to
get here well done slow down guys it could be booby trapped hey boss be a good friend and
hand me three of those scrolls will you
i just wanted to say thanks okay time to move let's go and stay on your toes all right
go and stay on your toes all right
La-ya-la-ya-la